HENRY RICHARD

Dependable, safety-conscious janitor with eight years of experience in school and hotel fac i l iti es grou nd s clea n i n g, m a i ntena n ce a nd repa i rs. Prof i ci e nt w ith hand too ls, power tool s New York, New York, 12345 and industrial equipment, and possess an HVAC/R certificate.

123 Blue Bird Street. h en ryrichard @exa m ple.co m (123)456-7890

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

JANITOR

Big Apple Hotel, New York, New York February 2015 - Present

- Sweep, mo p a n d vacu u m floo rs through ou t the 550- room hotel
- Remove trash from rooms, lounge, restaurant and gift shop areas safely
- Repair hotel cooling and heating systems as needed
- Maintain and repair hotel plumbing and electrical systems as needed
- Trained five new janitors successfully in cleaning, sanitation and safety
- Received Big Apple Hotel Excellence in Safety Award in 2018 for quick-response guest spills cleanups

JANITOR

B ig App le M idd I e Schoo I, New York, New York March 2012 - February 2015

- Mowed and trimmed school lawn and shrubs, cleared trash and debris from grounds
- Swept and mopped hallways, classrooms, gymnasium and teacher's offices
- C leaned offi ce a nd c lassroo m fu rn i tu re, f ixtu res, wi n d ows and wa 11 s
- Saved school roughly 53,000 per year by performing minor heating, cooling and plumbing repairs
- Performed daily electrical appliance safety checks before locking up 2,000+ student school

EDUCATION

High School Diploma

Big Apple High School. New York., NY August 2007 to August 2011

KEY SKILLS

- Cleaning and sanitation
- Wide knowledge of working with various cleaning chemicals and machines
- Reliability
- Strong interpersonal skills
- Va I i d dr iver's I i cense with a clean driving record

CERTIFICATIONS

♦ New York State HVAC/R Certification, 2012